tacoda.net 2007-05-14

# TACODA - where the people are

  * More Information
  * Home
  * tacoda.com
  * FAQ
  * Privacy Policy
  * Contact Us
  * Content Watch

**TACODA's Privacy Policy**  
Last updated January 19, 2006

TACODA, Inc. ("TACODA") is a provider of targeted marketing technology and services to websites and online marketers, and considers the protection of your privacy to be of paramount importance. We operate two distinct services, TACODA Audience Management Services™, an advertising targeting service for websites, and TACODA Audience Networks™, an advertising network service for marketers and affiliated websites. This Privacy Policy was prepared to describe how we use and collect consumer data in providing these services.

**TACODA as a technology provider - TACODA Audience Management Services**

TACODA Audience Management Services (AMS) help websites collect consumer information and target advertisements on their websites or groups of websites. The information TACODA processes on such websites'' behalf belongs to those websites and is not further used by TACODA.

**TACODA as an advertising network - TACODA Audience Networks**  
TACODA Audience Networks (or the "network") is a collection of first tier websites that have joined in an effort to improve ad delivery while maintaining stringent standards on the usage of user data. The network matches ads to visitors'' network browsing behavior; however, TACODA Audience Networks does not own or share any visitor data.

**Data Collection and Usage**

  * Personal Information 

Personal information is data about you that is personally identifiable like your name, address, email address, or phone number, that is not otherwise publicly available. As part of AMS, TACODA may collect, host and manage the personal information that our website partners have chosen to collect from their sites. This data is the property of our website partners and is subject to their respective privacy policies. TACODA may not use this data in any way that is not authorized and requested by the websites from whose sites the data originated.

TACODA Audience Networks never uses, collects or keeps personal information about people who interact with any of the sites in the network. 

  * Non-Personal Information 

When you are on one of the websites (using TACODA products and services), the website, using cookies (see below), collects certain non-personal information from you, including but not limited to your browser type (for example, Internet Explorer or Mozilla) and your operating system (for example, Windows or Macintosh). In addition, the sites in the network collect information about your browsing behavior, such as the date and time you visit the websites, the content areas or pages of the websites that you visit (for example, ''sports section'' or ''technology section''), the ads that were on pages you visited, and other click-stream data, none of which will include personal information about you.

  * Registration Data 

Some of the websites collect additional information about you through registration, for activities such as access to premium content, entering sweepstakes, or for fulfilling offers like email newsletter subscriptions. This information sometimes includes personal information such as your address or phone number, and non-personal demographic information such as age, gender and zip code. To refine the targeting of ads that are most appropriate for you, AMS and TACODA Audience Networks may access the non-personal information that may have been collected in a registration environment. Personal information such as name, address and phone number is never accessed.

  * Customer Information 

Prospective customers (websites and online marketers) can go to the www.tacoda.com site and provide their contact information to find out more and to be contacted by a TACODA representative. TACODA or its service providers reserve the right to use this information for business purposes such as marketing and research. TACODA and its service providers are prohibited from using this information for other purposes or from sharing this information with other companies. This information is not used for purposes other than responding to the request.

  * Temporary Use and Disbursement of Non-Personal Information

In order to serve visitors appropriate ads, TACODA Audience Networks will temporarily assemble non-personal, demographic, behavioral and technical information to create very large audience segments. These segments represent data that has been aggregated into large anonymous groupings. After the ad or ads have been served, only aggregate segment level data is retained by TACODA Audience Networks.

TACODA Audience Networks does not provide any personal information to marketers when you interact with or view a targeted ad.

To make certain that ads served by TACODA Audience Networks are targeted correctly, partner websites in the network place TACODA Audience Networks data tags on their sites. These tags are not personally identifiable nor do they collect personal information. They are used to match visitor browsing behavior to a segment profile designated for targeting ads to visitors. 

  * Cookies

Nearly all websites, including those using AMS and in TACODA Audience Networks, use a feature of your browser to set a "cookie" on your computer. Cookies are small packets of data stored on your computer. The site placing the packet on your computer can then recognize the computer when you revisit the site. The site''s computer uses the cookie to provide services such as auto log on and relevant ad delivery, and to better understand how you are interacting with the site. These cookies effectively enable sites to better customize the site to your needs and interests, so that it can be as valuable to you as possible.

You are always free to decline cookies, but by doing so you may not be able to use certain features on the websites or take full advantage of all the website offerings and targeted advertising. You can configure your browser to accept all cookies, reject all cookies, erase cookies, or notify you when a cookie is set. (Each browser is different, so check the ''Help'' menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences.)

Alternatively, you may [click here to opt-out of data collection and targeting cookies from TACODA Audience Networks](http://www.networkadvertising.org/consumer/opt_out.asp). Be advised that if you change computers or browsers, or use multiple computers or browsers, you will need to repeat this process for each computer and each browser. 

  * Privacy Compliance 

TACODA is a member of the [Network Advertising Initiative (NAI)](http://www.networkadvertising.org/) and is in compliance with the NAI''s Self-Regulatory Principles which have been developed in collaboration with the Federal Trade Commission. 

  * Disclosure of Information 

Non-personal information may be transferred or disclosed to the following entities for the following purposes: (1) to our affiliate websites to segment and target relevant advertisements to you; (2) to entities authorized to handle data such as: our employees, independent contractors, subsidiaries, affiliates, consultants, business associates, service providers and suppliers. Disclosure would be made only to enable any of these entities to perform a business, professional or technical support function for us; (3) to respond to judicial process and provide information to law enforcement agencies or in connection with an investigation on matters related to public safety, as permitted by law, or otherwise as required by law; and (4) as provided for under the ''Unforeseen Circumstances'' section below.

**Security**

We take appropriate security measures to protect against unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of data. This includes the necessary physical, electronic and managerial procedures to protect data integrity, access and use.

TACODA is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to build users'' trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. This privacy statement covers the site www.tacoda.com. It also addresses how TACODA handles information of websites that use AMS. Because this website wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact **[privacy@tacoda.com.](mailto:privacy@tacoda.com)** If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact TRUSTe at <http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php>. TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with the website to resolve your concerns. 

**Unforeseen Circumstances**

As we continue to develop our business, we or our affiliates may sell or buy other businesses or entities. In such transactions, any non-personal information we have collected from you may be one of the transferred business assets. No personal information would ever be transferred as a TACODA asset.

**The Right to Change This Policy**

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here or by means of a notice on our home page.

#### Opt-out of TACODA’s network

By clicking opt-out you will not receive targeted advertising delivered by TACODA.

To learn more about TACODA’s advertising, [click here for Frequently Asked Questions](http://www.tacoda.com/notice/FAQ).

To read our Privacy Policy statement, [click here](http://www.tacoda.com/notice/privacy_policy.html).

We value your opinion. To contact us with your questions, concerns, or suggestions, please [email our Chief Privacy Officer](mailto:privacy@tacoda.com).
